FAVOUR OLOTU

Software Engineer, B.Eng

613-325-4802 • folotu99@gmail.com • https://favourolotu.github.io/ • linkedin.com/in/favour-olotu • Ottawa, ON

SUMMARY

Bachelor of Software Engineering graduate with 2+ years of experience designing and implementing complex software architectures in multiple languages across multiple platforms, including embedded systems and sensor fusion in robotics. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Experienced in working with both small and large teams across multiple projects and companies.

SKILLS

Tools: Java • Python • SQL • C/C++ • HTML • PHP • JavaScript • Git • CSS • Docker • JIRA • Wireshark • Splunk Operating Systems: Unix • Linux • Windows

EDUCATION

Coursera, Online – Google Cybersecurity Specialization Certification

December 2023

Reference: https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/R2RBHE6ZS6PE

Carleton University, Ottawa, ON – Bachelor of Software Engineering, Co-op Option **September 2018 - April 2023**

Sault College, Sault Ste. Marie, ON – Mechanical Engineering Technician September 2016 - April 2018

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Four DRobotics Corp, Ottawa, ON – *Robotics Software Engineer* **April 2022 - PRESENT**

Developed and tested software for the components of an autonomous ground vehicle

Innovapost, Kanata, ON – *IT Operations and Infrastructure Engineering Coop* **January 2021 - December 2021**

• Designed software for simulating a data centre based on the analysis from previous usage reports to aid with the development of data centre strategies

Carleton University, Ottawa, ON – *Teaching Assistant* **September 2020 - April 2023**

Assisted professors in implementing lessons and graded course deliverables